ete.gaurav@hotmail.com+506 88871370

### About me

Global IT professional with over 9 years of experience in data engineering, analysis & reporting, project delivery & management, risk mitigation and project leadership within consumer goods industry. Self-motivated, detail- oriented and ability to work in a rapidly changing environment with problem solving and learning mindset.

### **EXPERIENCE**

LTI - Larsen & Toubro Infotech Client - Procter & Gamble SA Location - San Jose, Costa Rica Sep 2019 - Jun 2020 IT Operations Manager - Procure to Pay

- Responsible for managing the day-to-day operations activities for all the P&G Global BW applications.
- Responsible for implementing process improvement ideas within the operations team which resulted in annual cost savings of over \$200K.
- Responsible for automating the testing process during the platform upgrades resulting in reduction of FTE and in turn helping the organization with cost savings
- Responsible for managing High priority tickets and escalations by providing periodic updates.
- Responsible for handling a distributed team comprising of over 25 consultants distributed across EST & IST time zones.
- Responsible for conducting and leading the Service review meetings with multiple stakeholders on periodic basis.
- Helped team to work collaboratively and created an Agile culture for delivering requirements.
- Shielded the team from outside interference so that the day-to-day activities are executed as per the plan..
- Provided guidance and direction to the team by applying strategy and data driven analysis. With servant leadership and mentorship, was able to create learning environment within teams.
- Helped teams to cultivate an environment of respect and empathy for each other. Worked as a mentor and helped the team to understand the importance of being self-organizing.
- Responsible for risk management and implementing effective communication plan with internal and external stakeholders.
- Highly driven, self-motivated with excellent written and verbal communication skills.
- Worked with management to develop the and strengthen the agile culture within the organization.
- Coached and exchanged ideas on creating high performing teams who can deliver better quality products.

<u>Technologies used</u>: SAP BW4HANA /SAP Netweaver 7.4, SAP S4/HANA, JIRA, PowerBI, Tableau, Sharepoint, Scrum framework, DevOps,

ete.gaurav@hotmail.com+506 88871370

LTI - Larsen & Toubro Infotech
Client - Procter & Gamble SA
Location - San Jose, Costa Rica
Aug 2018 - Aug 2019
IT Application Manager - Sourcing, Procurement & Payment Services

- Responsible for managing BW Sourcing, Procurement & Payment Services applications.
- As part of the Procurement analytics project under the P2P space in the S/4 HANA landscape, was responsible for the data replication from different P2P tables (EKKO, EKPO, EKKN, EKBE) from the SAP R/3 systems to the S/4 HANA box for operational reporting.
- By using the SOLMAN CDC (Cross Data Comparison) tool, I was able to design and implement an automated reconciliation mechanism for the data between different tables in the source systems with the corresponding tables in the S/4 HANA system.
- Collaborating with the operations team in order to execute Non-negative application testing, OSS note implementation and third level change requests.
- Stakeholder management for enhancement of existing reporting solutions. Helped with proposing solutions and with development of proof of concepts.
- Gathered, reviewed, negotiated, and provided recommendations on requirements from the business/product owners.
- Prepared time & cost estimates and negotiated cost with the stakeholders and ensured successful project delivery.
- Played servant leader role and helped development team to embrace change/challenge, work collaboratively and start deliveries in Agile manner
- In situation of utter Chaos, find a way out of it and drive team from Chaotic state to Performing stage
- Mentored newly onboarded application managers with different P&G specific processes.
- Tracking of the progress of the project by conducting daily stand-up meetings with the project team.
- As an Application owner, was involved in completing the annual CSA (Controlled Self-Assessment) for the different P2P apps.

<u>Technologies used</u>: SAP S/4HANA, SAP Netweaver 7.4, Power BI, Tableau, SAP Bex Query Designer, Advanced Analytics, Knime, SCRUM

LTI - Larsen & Toubro Infotech Client - Procter & Gamble SA Location - San Jose, Costa Rica Jul 2016 - Jul 2018 SAP BI/BW Consultant | Project Lead

- Involved in complete lifecycle implementation of the project from gathering user requirements, preparation of technical specifications documents, designing and developing reports, Integration testing, unit testing to go live and production support.
- Involved with stakeholder by sharing timely updates from the beginning to the end of the project.
- Gathered and analyzed the received requirements from business owners and product owners and presented options for project delivery to them. Led the architectural design reviews with the P&G's central governance team.
- Developed BI solutions such as data models, information objects and info cubes for projects to fulfill business needs and requirements.

ete.gaurav@hotmail.com+506 88871370

- Worked on ETL (Extraction, transformation and loading) activities like Extraction from Source system, Transformation rules, Data Transfer Process (DTP), Open Hub service etc.
- Created data sources using generic and application specific extraction (LIS) for SD and MM modules and loaded the business content.
- Analyzed business reporting requirements that could be satisfied and activated/modified corresponding Business content data targets within SAP BW.
- Extracted Data from Finance, Controlling, Purchasing and Inventory Management.
- Developed and scheduled Business Content data extraction from SAP R/3 Source System and data load procedures
- Worked as a Servant leader and helped the team by mentoring and teaching them the Scrum process and frameworks.
- Implemented over ten key projects of the Procurement portfolio to improve and enhance existing applications according to the needs of the changing market.
- Migrated more than 100 objects of the Procure to Pay application from SAP BW 7.0 (Oracle) to SAP BW 7.3 (HANA).
- Worked with the PMO during the review of the SOW (statement of work) and ensured that SGM (super gross margins) and PAT (profit after tax) metrics were acceptable regarding the organization's standard.
- Worked with resource managers for on-boarding and allocation of resources to prepare selfsufficient and cross functional teams.

<u>Technologies used</u>: SAP BW 7.0, SAP BW 7.3 (HANA), Business Explorer, Analysis for office, Scrum

LTI - Larsen & Toubro Infotech
Client - Procter & Gamble SA
Location - San Jose, Costa Rica
Aug 2014 - Aug 2016
IT Operations Lead for Sourcing (Phoenix/ATLAS/ P2P) Applications

- Responsible for extraction of data from SAP transactional data sources into BW for analytics and reporting.
- Responsible for the data cleaning and engineering of data in the SAP Business warehouse system. Developed business warehouse objects (Data Store Objects, Infocubes, Process Chains, Bex Queries) and data modeling (Dimensional & Relational) concepts including Starschema modeling, Snowflakes modeling, facts and dimension tables.
- Monitoring Data load activities and recovered failures in Dev, Quality system as a part of unit testing.
- Preparing the process documents for every enhancement. Worked on streamlining the Spend pool master data management by collaborating with multiple teams and bringing transparency in the process.
- Involving in solving high-prioritized tickets regarding extractions, performance issues and data load failures.
- Identified manual activities such as deletion of indexes ODS activation, further updating, PSA request deletion and Attribute change run and automated the processes to reduce manual intervention.
- Implemented open hub to export data from BI to External systems (flat file, table, 3rd party tool).
- Executed Unit testing, Integration testing, Regression testing and User acceptance tests.

ete.gaurav@hotmail.com+506 88871370

- Worked on enhancing the existing Sourcing /Procurement reports based on the new requirements.
- Monitoring the daily loads to various data targets in the system. Monitoring of process chains on periodic basis (daily, weekly & monthly).
- Manual loading and rolling up the data into data targets & maintaining the logs for each manual load. Creating aggregates to improve the query response.
- Performance tuning of queries using aggregates, indexing of Infocubes.
- Prepared test cases and executed the same during the stress testing window during the platform upgrades. Responsible for sharing timely updates of the testing and also was involved in the resolution process with SAP (in case of any issues during the upgrades).
- Worked with multi-cultural and diverse teams. Implemented several automation ideas resulting in streamlined processes and in the reduction of manual intervention.
- Automated data loading and monitored strategies across multiple applications, which successfully reduced \$150 K per year in operation costs.

<u>Technologies used</u>: SAP BW, Netweaver 7.1, 7.2, BeX query designer, Oracle, Advanced Analytics.

LTI - Larsen & Toubro Infotech
Client - Procter & Gamble
Location - Bengaluru, India
Sep 2010 - Jul 2014
SAP BW on HANA Technical Consultant

- Responsible for extraction of data from SAP transactional data sources into BW for analytics and reporting.
- Responsible for the data cleaning and engineering of data in the SAP Business warehouse system. Developed business warehouse objects (Data Store Objects, Infocubes, Process Chains, Bex Queries) and data modeling (Dimensional & Relational) concepts including Starschema modeling, Snowflakes modeling, facts and dimension tables.
- Responsible for designing, coding, and modeling Business Intelligence data warehouse applications. Played a key role in support and maintenance of existing solutions. Focused on issue resolution and customer satisfaction.
- Responsible for designing, coding, and modeling Business Intelligence data warehouse applications during the migration of database from ORACLE systems to HANA database for Procure to pay applications.
- Experienced in Query and report development using SAP Business Explorer, Analysis in Office.
- Worked on creating Data Models Creating InfoObjects, Datasource, Infopackage, DTP, Transformations, DSO, Infocubes, Multi providers etc.
- Worked in ABAP routines Start routine, End routine, field routine and Expert Routines in transformations written codes for master data look-up, filtering data based on complex conditions, used function module for various conversions, etc.
- Created Open Hub Destination to load the BW data to 3rd party system.
- Created, published and scheduled reports as per requirement on BO OLAP analysis and Explorer. Implemented cells, workbooks and OLAP variables (like Customer exits, formula variables etc.) in BEx.
- Created and scheduled Master data and Transactional Data chains to automate data load process.

ete.gaurav@hotmail.com +506 88871370

<u>Technologies used</u>: SAP BW, Netweaver 3.5, 7.0, BeX query designer, Oracle, Advanced Analytics.

## **COURSES & TRAININGS**

#### Microsoft

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals, 2020

#### LinkedIn

Scrum: Advanced, 2020 Python for Students, 2020

### **Coursera Course Certificate**

Machine Learning: Regression, 2020 Machine Learning Foundations, 2020

#### Coursera

Data Science Orientation, 2020

### Scrum.org

Professional Scrum Master II, 2020 Professional Scrum Master I, 2019

#### SAP SE

SAP Certified Application Associate - SAP HANA 2.0 (SPS03), 2020

#### SAP

Modern Data Warehousing with SAP BW/4HANA, 2019

### **EDUCATION**

#### **BPUT**

Bachelor's in Electronics and Telecommunication Engineering, 2008

## **SKILLS**

• Scrum	Business Intelligence	<ul><li>Python</li></ul>
<ul> <li>Agile Project Management</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Data Warehousing</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Github</li> </ul>
<ul> <li>Requirements Analysis</li> </ul>	SAP S/4 HANA	<ul> <li>DevOps</li> </ul>
• SDLC	Ms Power BI	CI/CD
Project Management	SAP HANA 2.0	<ul> <li>MySQL</li> </ul>
Team Management	SAP BW/4HANA	Oracle
Test Planning/ UAT		<ul> <li>Machine Learning</li> </ul>